Guide to the Marilyn Crafton Smith papers RL.11194
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Marilyn Crafton Smith Papers
1978-1993 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Smith, Marilyn Crafton
RL.11194
7.5 Linear Feet
Marilyn Crafton Smith is a retired faculty member at Appalachian State University in Boone, NC whose collection includes documentation of the activities of the National Organization for Women, the fight for the Equal Rights Amendment, feminism in Western North Carolina, and LGBT printed matter.
Biographical / Historical
Marilyn Crafton Smith is a scholar, feminist activist, and collector who is a Professor Emeritus of Art at Appalachian State University in Boone, North Carolina. She has written about feminism in media and communication studies, as well as cultural politics in media.
Content Description
Materials documenting the life and work of scholar, activist, and collector of feminist and LGBTQ print culture including student work, teaching files, clippings, Boone Area and Iowa City National Organization for Women (NOW) files, Western NC LGBTQ organization and event files,Southeastern Women's Studies Association (SEWSA) files, Southeastern College Art Conference (SECAC) files, Center for Research on Women (Duke and Memphis State University) files, social movement t-shirts, magazines, newspapers, journals, pamphlets, and books; and a Bride Bingo game.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Marilyn Crafton Smith papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2014.
Equal rights amendments -- North Carolina; Feminism and higher education; Feminists -- North Carolina; Women's rights -- North Carolina; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; National Organization for Women; Appalachian State University
- Feuding Over Family: A Discursive Analysis of Contested Meanings of Family in Prime-Time Television, 1992 (Box 1)
- Politics of the Image, Professor: Marilyn Smith, 1987 (Box 1)
- Art, Media, Politics, Marilyn Smith, Prof, 1992 (Box 1)
- Minorities in Art and Media, 1993 (Box 1)
- Lectures/Notes/Minorities in Art and Media, M Smith, 1993 (Box 1)
- Women and Media: Literature of Communication, undated (Box 1)
- Women and Media, 1984 (Box 2)
- Women and Media, undated (Box 2)
- Body Politics Tee-Shirt Show, 1991 (Box 2)
- Clippings and Ephemera, 1980-1983; 2 folders (Box 2)
- Abortion/Reproduction Rights, undated (Box 2)
- Anti-Feminism, 1980-1982 (Box 2)
- Catalogs, Women's Organizations, 1980-1982 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 2)
- Music, 1983-1986 (Box 2)
- NY - Women's Studies, 1980 (Box 2)
- Reagan, undated (Box 2)
- Women Against Violence Against Women (WAVAW), 1980-1985 (Box 2)
- Women's Music (Popular Songs and Women), 1981-1985 (Box 2)
- Birthday Craft, undated (Box 3)
- Boone Area NOW, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
- NOW International Conference - Indianapolis, 1982 (Box 3)
- FM Stuff, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
- NOW - National Organization for Women, undated (Box 3)
- NOW Minutes (Boone), 1980-1982 (Box 3)
- NOW Bylaws, 1980 (Box 3)
- ERA Campaign, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 3)
- Ads - Signature, 1981 (Box 3)
- NOW - GA: Project, Reaganomics Work, Medical Survey (Boone), 1982 (Box 3)
- NOW Letters, 1981 (Box 3)
- ERA - United Church Board for Homeland Ministries, 1978 (Box 3)
- Family Protection Act, 1981 (Box 3)
- Gender Gap, 1981 (Box 4)
- Margaret (Pinky) Hayden, 1980 (Box 4)
- NOW - Membership, 1980-1982 (Box 4)
- NOW Newsletters (Boone), 1981-1982 (Box 4)
- NOW Programs, 1982 (Box 4)
- NOW/Boone Promo, 1980 (Box 4)
- NC NOW Proposal, 1983 (Box 4)
- Recession, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
- NOW/ERA Brochures, 1980 (Box 4)
- Speech: ERA/NOW, 1979-1981 (Box 4)
- Statement on the Equal Rights Amendment, 1978 (Box 4)
- The Equal Rights Amendment, 1981 (Box 4)
- ERA Rally, 1982 (Box 4)
- ERA Action Team Manual, 1981 (Box 4)
- ERA Countdown Campaign, undated (Box 4)
- NOW Policy Manual, 1979 (Box 5)
- NOW Legislation/Policies, 1981-1986 (Box 5)
- Guidelines for Organizing a NOW Chapter, undated (Box 5)
- NOW, undated (Box 5)
- Boone LGA/LAMDA, 1990-1991 (Box 5)
- Lesbian Rights, 1990-1992 (Box 5)
- Boone NOW, 1989 (Box 5)
- Duke-UNC Branches/Memphis State Newsletter, 1984-1997 (Box 5)
- SEWSA/SECAC, 1985-1990 (Box 5)
- Iowa City NOW, 1984 (Box 5)
- Publications, 1979-1983 (Box 5)